You may have heard of an event horizon
你也许听说过事件视界
the boundary beyond which not even light can escape a black hole
在黑洞视界内即使光也不能逃脱
This is a very interesting surface to think about
这是一个相当有趣的界面
but i want to talk to you about the other boundary around a black hole
但是今天我要向你介绍黑洞中的另一个界面
it's known as a stationary limit surface
我们称之为静界
In order for this boundary to be noticeable
为了让这个界面比较明显
our black hole has to be spinning
我们的黑洞需要有一定的自旋
so let's imagine that we're looking at it from above or from one of the poles
想象我们从上方或者转轴方向看去
the spinning of the black hole actually ends up dragging the space time surrounding it
黑洞的自旋将会拖曳周围的时空
it if any object even a photon of light enters this region known as the ergosphere
任何物体 即使是光子 只要进入到能层
the region between the event horizon and the stationary limit surface
即事件视界和静界之间的区域
then for somebody looking from far away
在远处的某人看来
the object will always appear to rotate in the same direction as the black hole
这个物体总是顺着黑洞的方向旋转
even if it was going the other way before entering the ergosphere
即使它是从相反的方向进入能层的
that's because the space time in which this object exists
这是因为这个物体所处的时空
is literally being dragged around with the rotation of the black hole
被黑洞的旋转扭曲了
that's why this effect is known as frame dragging
这就是为什么这个效应被称作参考系拖拽